Get ready to power up!
Barbie Video Game Hero is a animation, family, science
fiction film directed by Ezekiel Norton.
When Barbie is accidentally pulled into her favourite game, she teams up with the roller skater Bella and
her friend Cutie, to stop a mischievous emoji who is trying to take control of the game.
Barbie (voice), played by Erica Lindbeck.
Teresa / Countdown Clock (voice), played by Sienna Bohn.
Maia / Renee (voice), played by Shannon Chan-Kent.
Cutie / Video Game Narrator (voice), played by Michael Dobson.
Chelsea (voice), played by Alyssya Swales.
Bella (voice), played by Rebekah Asselstine.
Barbie is a 2023 satirical fantasy comedy film directed by Greta Gerwig
from a screenplay she wrote with her husband, Noah Baumbach.
Based on the fashion dolls by Mattel, it is the first live-action
Barbie film after numerous animated films and specials.
Starring Margot Robbie as the title character and Ryan Gosling as Ken, the film follows them on a journey
of self-discovery through Barbieland and the real world following an existential crisis.
The supporting cast includes America Ferrera, Michael Cera, Kate
McKinnon, Issa Rae, Rhea Perlman, and Will Ferrell.
A live-action Barbie film was announced in September 2009 by
Universal Pictures with Laurence Mark producing.
Development began in April 2014, when Sony Pictures acquired the film rights.
Following multiple writer and director changes and the casting of Amy Schumer and later
Anne Hathaway as Barbie, the rights were transferred to Warner Bros.
Pictures in October 2018.
Robbie was cast in 2019, after Gal Gadot turned down the role due to scheduling conflicts,
and Gerwig was announced as director and co-writer with Baumbach in 2020.
The rest of the cast was announced in early 2022.
Principal photography occurred primarily at Warner Bros.
Studios, Leavesden, England, and at the Venice Beach
Skatepark in Los Angeles from March to July 2022.
Barbie premiered at the Shrine Auditorium in Los Angeles on July 9,
2023, and was released in the United States on July 21.
Its concurrent release with Universal Pictures' Oppenheimer was the catalyst of the
"Barbenheimer" phenomenon, encouraging audiences to see both films as a double feature.
The film grossed $1.448 billion and achieved several milestones, becoming the highest-grossing film
of 2023 and the 14th highest-grossing film of all time at the time of its release.
Named one of the top ten films of 2023 by the National Board of Review and the American Film Institute, Barbie received critical acclaim and other accolades, including eight Academy Award nominations (among them Best Picture),
winning Best Original Song for "What Was I Made For?"; the song also won the Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song while the film received the inaugural Golden Globe Award for Cinematic and Box Office Achievement.
The film explores themes of video game, based on toy,
female protagonist, virus, computer programmer.
The tone is thought_provoking.